<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>The WebFX blog</title>
  <icon>https://blog.webfx.dev/favicon.png</icon>
  <subtitle>Follow WebFX - a free and open-source JavaFX transpiler project on GitHub.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blog.webfx.dev/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://blog.webfx.dev/"/>
  <updated>2022-10-18T20:53:50.773Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.webfx.dev/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Salmon</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>DemoFX: our new WebFX demo!</title>
    <link href="https://blog.webfx.dev/2022/09/26/demofx/"/>
    <id>https://blog.webfx.dev/2022/09/26/demofx/</id>
    <published>2022-09-26T13:40:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-18T20:53:50.773Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://demofx.webfx.dev/"><img src="/2022/09/26/demofx/DemoFX.png" alt="DemoFX"></a></p><p>You may not have noticed but we published a <a href="https://demofx.webfx.dev/">new demo</a> on the WebFX <a href="https://webfx.dev/">website</a> a few weeks ago.</p><p>This demo is based on the excellent <a href="https://github.com/chriswhocodes/DemoFX">DemoFX library</a> by Chris Newman, a JavaFX canvas library that offers a collection of effects which were primarily designed for JavaFX canvas benchmarks, but can be used and chained to make animations too. We made a <a href="https://github.com/webfx-libs/webfx-lib-demofx">partial port</a> of this library in <a href="https://github.com/webfx-libs">WebFX Libs</a>, our dedicated space for WebFX libraries.</p><p>We first made this <a href="https://demofxkitchensink.webfx.dev/">DemoFX kitchen sink</a> to test and visualize each effect individually, and then chose to sequence them in a particular order, with the music of David Newman played in the background (also provided by the DemoFX library). We set accurate transition times to match the musical rhythm. The demo starts with an introductory animation, asking to click in order to play the actual demo, because in the browser sandbox, playing sound is not permitted before interacting with the user. The resulted demo is just one single <a href="https://github.com/webfx-demos/webfx-demo-demofx/blob/main/webfx-demo-demofx-application/src/main/java/dev/webfx/demo/demofx/DemoFXApplication.java">java source file</a>.</p><p>Most effects should run fluidly, except maybe the fractal rings (2nd effect in the demo) on low-powered devices or big screens, especially when another effect is running simultaneously (such as the fading star field at the beginning, or the Sierpinski effect at the end). You may try the <a href="https://github.com/webfx-demos/webfx-demo-demofx/releases">native version</a> of the demo to get better results. But on modern devices (we tested on an iPad mini 6) the performance is excellent already with the web version. A modern backlit display also renders the fractal rings effect much better.</p><p>This WebFX demo mainly emphasises the canvas support and the MediaPlayer sound support, including the audio spectrum analysis as demonstrated by the equaliser. Some effects rely on the PixelWriter API. WebFX emulates this JavaFX API, but also provides its own alternative PixelWriter API, slightly different but with better performance for the web (more explanation on this topic will be given in a separate post). So we rewrote these effects using the WebFX PixelWriter API to ensure optimal performance. The final demo JS size is 129kB, and this shows once again how WebFX can produce lightweight and performant web apps that load and start quickly.</p><p><strong>Follow us on Twitter</strong></p><p>By the way, we just created a Twitter account for WebFX. So if you’re interested, you can follow us on <a href="https://twitter.com/WebFXProject">@WebFXProject</a>.</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://demofx.webfx.dev/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2022/09/26/demofx/DemoFX.png&quot; alt=&quot;DemoFX&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may not have noticed but we pub</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The WebFX website is live!</title>
    <link href="https://blog.webfx.dev/2022/07/22/website-launch/"/>
    <id>https://blog.webfx.dev/2022/07/22/website-launch/</id>
    <published>2022-07-22T12:52:12.000Z</published>
    <updated>2022-10-18T20:53:50.773Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://webfx.dev/"><img src="/2022/07/22/website-launch/webfx-website.png" alt="WebFX website"></a></p><p>We are very happy to announce that the WebFX <a href="https://webfx.dev/">website</a> is now live. The whole project has been paused for nearly a year due to some circumstances, but the very good news is that the conditions have finally been gathered to restart it. So the WebFX project has resumed this year, and we managed to accomplish the next stage: publishing the website. </p><p>The website comes along with this blog and the <a href="https://docs.webfx.dev/">documentation</a> which is minimal for now but will grow over the time. Today, it’s mainly a guide to get you started, which is probably the thing you were awaiting the most, if you are following the project.</p><p>We hope you will enjoy your first experience with WebFX. The project is still in the incubation phase, and we are aware you will encounter some obstacles (limited JavaFX coverage, bugs in WebFX, GWT compilation errors in your code if you are not used to it, …), but we hope you will appreciate its great potential for Java-based environments.</p><p>Despite the limitations, you can already develop real applications. The website for example has been developed using WebFX. It presents the technology through a series of animated cards. If you are interested in its JavaFX code, you can check out its <a href="https://github.com/webfx-project/webfx-website">GitHub repository</a>.</p><!---The initial website had a couple of additional cards, but some found them be a bit controversial, so we considered their feedback, and finally removed them. These cards are still online [here](https://preview.webfx.dev) however for the curious.[![Additional cards](/2022/07/22/website-launch/webfx-preview.png)](https://preview.webfx.dev)--><p>Thank you all for starring the project, this was a very helpful feedback. It contributed to the decision made by the organization in which we are working to rebase its own main business system onto WebFX! It’s a quite big Java-based application, and we are in the process of open sourcing it as well. So it will be the first real world WebFX enterprise application, and it will be available on GitHub. We will give you more information on this soon in this blog. So don’t hesitate to subscribe the <a href="atom.xml">feed</a> to keep updated!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webfx.dev/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2022/07/22/website-launch/webfx-website.png&quot; alt=&quot;WebFX website&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very happy to</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
