<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>The WebFX blog</title>
  <icon>https://blog.webfx.dev/favicon.png</icon>
  <subtitle>Follow WebFX - a free and open-source JavaFX transpiler project on GitHub.</subtitle>
  <link href="https://blog.webfx.dev/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://blog.webfx.dev/"/>
  <updated>2022-05-30T13:40:47.863Z</updated>
  <id>https://blog.webfx.dev/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Bruno Salmon</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The WebFX website is live!</title>
    <link href="https://blog.webfx.dev/2022/05/30/website-launch/"/>
    <id>https://blog.webfx.dev/2022/05/30/website-launch/</id>
    <published>2022-05-30T13:40:47.863Z</published>
    <updated>2022-05-30T13:40:47.863Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="https://webfx.dev/"><img src="/2022/05/30/website-launch/webfx-website.png" alt="WebFX website"></a></p><p>We are very happy to announce that the WebFX <a href="https://webfx.dev/">website</a> is now live. The project has been paused for nearly a year due to some circumstances, but the good news is that the conditions have finally been gathered to restart it. So the WebFX project has resumed this year, and we managed to accomplish the next stage, publishing the website. </p><p>The website comes along with this blog and some <a href="https://docs.webfx.dev/">documentation</a>, including a guide to get you started, which is probably the thing you were awaiting the most, if you are following the project. It’s a bit succinct, but it should be enough to start.</p><p>The website itself can also be considered as an additional demo, because it’s actually a WebFX app. It presents the technology through a series of animated cards. If you are interested in the JavaFX code, you can check out the <a href="https://github.com/webfx-project/webfx-website">GitHub repository</a>.</p><p>The initial version had a couple of additional cards, but some people found them a bit controversial, so I considered their feedback, and finally removed them. These cards are still <a href="https://preview.webfx.dev/">online</a> however for the curious.</p><p><a href="https://preview.webfx.dev/"><img src="/2022/05/30/website-launch/webfx-preview.png" alt="Additional cards"></a></p><p>I hope you will find the website and its documentation useful, and you will enjoy your first experience with WebFX. The project is still in incubation phase, so be prepared to encounter some obstacles (limited JavaFX coverage and bugs in WebFX, GWT compilation errors in your code if you are not used to it, …), but I hope you will see there is a lot of potential here for us, Java developers. Thanks for your effort and patience.</p><p>And if you wish to be kept updated, you can bookmark this blog, or even better, subscribe to this <a href="atom.xml">feed</a> in your preferred RSS reader. We will try to publish regular posts (maybe something like once a month) to report any progress made on the project. You can consult our roadmap in the <a href="https://github.com/webfx-project/webfx">README</a>. Thanks for your support!</p>]]></content>
    
    
      
      
    <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://webfx.dev/&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2022/05/30/website-launch/webfx-website.png&quot; alt=&quot;WebFX website&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are very happy to</summary>
      
    
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
